Eric Corona

323.364.5722 | ericcorona@proton.me | linkedin.com/in/e-corona/ | Oericcorona1 | eric-corona.netlify.app

SUMMARY

As a Front-End Web Developer with experience in HTML, CSS, & JavaScript, I'm passionate about making an impact in my community. With crisis & resource management skills, proficiency in React and experience with testing frameworks like Cypress, I will be a valuable contribution to your projects.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Cypress
- Continuous integration

- Crisis & resource management
- Automated testing & quality assurance

EDUCATION

- <u>freeCodeCamp</u> Responsive Web Development & Javascript Algorithms
- William Jessup University, Rocklin, CA Graduated 2018 with a BA in Youth Ministry

EXPERIENCE

Transformative Education Counselor My Friend's Place, Los Angeles, CA | 2019-Present

- Developed proficiency in Google Apps Script to automate and integrate data tracking, email, and calendar functionalities, resulting in improved accuracy and streamlined communication processes.
- Strengthened Spanish language proficiency to facilitate engagement with Spanish-only speakers within the department, enhancing cross-team collaboration and communication.
- Collaborated with diverse teams and clients to identify and create actionable goals, establish clear expectations, and develop effective strategies to achieve desired outcomes.

Program Director One-Eighty Youth Programs, Lodi, CA | 2017-2019

- Updated website and social media, stabilized posting schedule, and increased engagement and following by 100%.
- Created a comfortable, safe, and fun atmosphere uniquely suitable for reaching varying demographics within the surrounding community, resulting in a 25% increase in program enrollment and retention.
- Built relationships with parents, youth, and schools to identify patterns, encourage growth, and provide resources, resulting in 90% positive feedback from program participants and stakeholders.

Youth Director Cornerstone Church of Lodi, Lodi, CA | 2014-2017

- Established relationships with students and parents in order to encourage, guide, and develop their daily spiritual growth, resulting in 75% increase in attendance and engagement.
- Facilitated events and meetings in order to follow the vision of the church and to meet the needs of the students and families, resulting in a 90% satisfaction rate from program participants.
- Developed a small team of leaders focused on supporting the students and parents, resulting in a 300% increase in volunteer participation and retention.